<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on ExampleSite</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on ExampleSite</description>
    <image>
      <url>%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative UX research - Tom Clancy&#39;s The Division 2</title>
      <link>/projects/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Master Thesis project that I completed at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.massive.se/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Massive Entertainment - A Ubisoft Studio&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-objective&#34;&gt;Research objective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychometrics tools (e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;https://quanticfoundry.com/#motivation-model&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gamer Motivation Model&lt;/a&gt;
) could tell us &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; players want to play a certain game; but it is not very clear that how the motivations are reflected during actual gameplay. This research trageted on players of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/the-division/the-division-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s The Division 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
, a tactical shooter action role-playing video game selling over 10 million copies worldwide, primarily aimed to address:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can players’ perceived experiences of playing &lt;em&gt;The Division 2&lt;/em&gt; affect their in-game behaviors?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-methodology&#34;&gt;Research methodology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, survey and telemetry data were utilized to operationalize the two main target variables: player motivation and player behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;survey&#34;&gt;Survey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.diva-portal.org/smash/get/diva2:1399422/FULLTEXT01.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Ubisoft Perceived Experiences Questionnaire (UPEQ)&lt;/a&gt;
was a psychometric instrument developed by Azadvar &amp;amp; Canossa (2018) to measure if if 4 basic psychological needs (i.e., &lt;em&gt;Autonomy,Competence, Relatedness, and Presence&lt;/em&gt;) are satisfied through playing video games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The questionnair is originally in English, validated by &lt;strong&gt;reliability test&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;confirmatory factor analysis (CFA)&lt;/strong&gt;, the UPEQ was also translated into Chinese before the formal distribution for reaching out to a more diverse sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;telemetry-data&#34;&gt;Telemetry data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aggregated game metrics below covered most in-game behaviors and could be categorized as 3 types: &lt;em&gt;playtime, progression, and DLC gameplay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;game_metrics.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-collection&#34;&gt;Data collection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole data collection process was GDPR compliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10,000&lt;/strong&gt; random active players across the globe who at least played one time during the month prior to the survey distribution were selected as the sample pool. By tracking their user ids, the UPEQ survey plus several demographic questions were distributed to each player via email through the CRM pipeline. The players were informed that the survey was targered on their play experiences of &lt;em&gt;The Division 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The telemetry data were extarcted through the offical game date bases. The survey responses were linked with the telemetry data by user ids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;269 players filled the survey, after cleaning outliers/over-consistent responses, 148 players remianed as the final sample size. The demographic characteristics of the respondents can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://lup.lub.lu.se/student-papers/search/publication/9090576&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-analysis&#34;&gt;Data analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hierarchical Linear regression analysis&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;logistic regression analysis&lt;/strong&gt; were applied to the data set to explore if player motivations were predictive of the in-game behaviors. An example of the R codes is displayed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#self-reported playtime
summary(mod_selftime &amp;lt;- lm(log(Weekly_playtime) ~ Relatedness, data))

vif(mod_selftime)
car::durbinWatsonTest(mod_selftime)
shapiro.test(rstandard(mod_selftime))

#group playtime ratio
summary(mod_gp2 &amp;lt;- lm(playtime_gp ~ Playstyle+Closeness, data))
summary(mod_gp1 &amp;lt;- lm(playtime_gp ~ Closeness, data))
anova(mod_gp1,mod_gp2)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-findings&#34;&gt;Key findings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For game designers, the research provides an insight into specific associations between motives of player engagement and game mechanics, which could be utilized to strengthen desired in-game behaviors of players. For &lt;em&gt;The Division 2&lt;/em&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storytelling establishes connection&lt;/strong&gt;: The more connected players feel with in-game characters, the more time they self-reported invested in the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immersion could facilitate engagement&lt;/strong&gt;: if players are more immersed in the game, it is more likely for them to level up faster (i.e., invest more time
during early stages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Players purchase more content for challenges&lt;/strong&gt;: whether players buy season-pass can be significantly predicted by &lt;em&gt;Competence&lt;/em&gt; scores. “If I feel effective and capable while playing, I would buy more content.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
